rubiconatlas.org 2019-03-26

# Rubicon Privacy Statement | Atlas

**Cookies and Passive Data Collection**  

Rubicon uses cookie, IP address, GPS location, URL information and other technical connection details to improve and further develop our products and services, and to provide enhanced or geographically differentiated features, event offerings, and product levels to our customers.  

Rubicon uses cookies to save customer screen names, session validators, and on customer’s browsers and hard drives, and may use them to provide targeted advertising about product features and services, as well as geographically specific event offerings.  

We may also obtain information for statistical purposes. For example, we may count the number of visitors to the different sections of our site to help us make them more useful to visitors in the future. Similar information is gathered for anonymous ftp, remote account log-ins, or for other comparable types of connections. 

Examples of personal data Rubicon collects and stores includes: 

  * Names 
  * Addresses 
  * E-mail Addresses 
  * Phone Numbers 
  * School/Company Name 

Rubicon also collects data when a customer provides us information in optional, voluntary submissions, such as event registration forms, newsletter subscriptions, promotional sign-ups, and other communications sent directly to us.  

Additionally, by sending us an electronic mail message, you may be sending us personal information (e.g., name, address, email address). We may store the name and address of the customer in order to respond to the question or request or to otherwise resolve the subject matter of your email.  

Regardless of the information being transmitted to Rubicon, we will protect all such information consistent with applicable law. You have the right to access your data, to make changes, or delete your data, and to opt out or unsubscribe from our emails and notifications at any time.  

As our systems develop and change, we may amend this Privacy Policy at any time without notice to you. Amendments to this Privacy Policy will be posted to this URL <https://www.rubicon.com/privacy/> and will be effective when posted. Continued use of the Rubicon website following the posting of any amendment, modification, or change shall constitute your acceptance of amendments.  

**Purposes of Collecting Data**  

The reason for collecting and storing data is to provide better service to our customers. Data provides insights to us when enhancing product features and functionality; when creating content for resources and newsletters; for event registrations and themes for professional development events; and other exchanges of information.  

**How Rubicon uses the information it collects**  

Rubicon creates newsletters and designs professional development events based on data collected. We also use customer feedback to guide our new product features, and to create new platforms for our suite of products. The personal information you provide to Rubicon will not be sold, rented, loaned or disclosed to any third parties outside of Rubicon.  

Rubicon does utilize other third-party companies (i) Salesforce, (ii) Hubspot, (iii), Microsoft, (iv) GoToMeeting, (v) Sage Intacct and discloses customer contact information to them for limited services on its behalf, including but not limited to web analytics, coordination of mailings, accounting, and event management. These third parties are permitted to access only the information they require to perform those services. Rubicon requires these companies to maintain the confidentiality of any personal information and prohibits them from using the information for any other purpose than the purpose for which it was collected.
